in this lesson we're going to focus on
simplifying natural logs
with e
so let's start with the basics what is
the natural log of one
log of one is always zero
a log
can have any base
it could be base 4 it can be base 10 it
could be anything
however
when it has the base e
a log becomes a natural log
so natural logs
only have base e and e is a number it's
like
2.718 something
but that's e
so now what is the natural log of e
because the base
is the same as e
ln base e of e is one
so the natural log of e is always equal
to one make sure you know that by the
way
now what is the natural log of e raised
to the seventh
we could take the seven and move it to
the front
so this is seven
lne
and we know that lne is one so this is
equal to seven
now what about
e
raised to the ln 8
what is that equal to
do you recall what 5
log base 5
of 9 is equal to
since these are the same
the answer is simply not
the natural log has the base e and so
these are the same
and the answer is simply 8.
now what about e raised to the natural
log of x cubed
so once again the base is e
and so these will
cancel and this is simply equal to x
cubed
let's try one more example
e raised to the seven l and y
what is that equal to
we can't just say it's y because of the
seven
however what we can do
is take the seven and move it here
so this is equivalent to e
ln y to the seventh
and the base is e
so we can get rid of these two
and the final answer
is simply y to the seventh
you